hamidashita kaze wo atsumete mitai na
I want to try and gather the unrestrained winds
nami no saki tsutatte kanata e kaketeku
I'll run toward the horizon alongside the wave crests
kakugo wa kimatteru
I've made my decision
michi wa tookutemo
even if there's a long way to go on that road
egaita mirai e tsudzuiteru
I'll continue towards the future I've planned
toki ga bokura wo sekashite kodou ga supiido agetetta
time rushes us, the heartbeat speeds up
yume no naka de mezametemo onaji hikari wo sagashita
when I woke in the middle of a dream, I kept searching for that same light
kagayaku hoshizora no shita kazoekirenai seiza to kage
under the shining star-lit sky, with countless constellations and shadows
sono saki ni kimi wa nani wo nani wo mitsumete iru darou
there was something beyond that, what were you gazing at?
nani wo mitsumete iru darou
what were you gazing at?
You guys did good work.
Komei has confessed.
It seems he plotted the Cursed Warrior
to mislead the public
and to take the feudal-lord position.
Is that what Komei said?
Yes. It turned out to be such a trifle.
The Cursed Warrior's vanishing
was a soldier disguising himself
as the warrior
using a strong nitrohydrochloric acid
to melt his own flesh.
It's empty again.
With this,
the Cursed Warrior incident is resolved.
Now the Land of Birds should return
to the beautiful and quiet land
it used to be.
Just a minute!
But the Cursed Warrior still isn't...!
— Don't bother.
— But...!
Now you are relieved of your duty.
Have a safe journey back to your village.
Why?!
You said the one we saw first
and the one last night were different,
right?
Perhaps there were multiple people
disguised as the Cursed Warrior,
not just one alone.
If there was a person inside disguised,
then how do you explain
the warrior flying?
As long as our mission
has been ordered complete,
there's no reason to continue the mission
in this land now.
Besides,
Komei confessed to the crime, right?
But it's suspicious.
I can't go along with it
if I don't get the whole story.
This land has its own circumstances.
Getting too involved will cause trouble.
— Then I'll just have to do it my way.
— Hold it.
I'm the leader of this team.
So what?
You look into the movements
of the Cursed Warrior once more.
Tenten and I will reinvestigate
this incident from a different angle.
What? But the mission's over.
You have a point with what you said.
Everything is moving along
too swimmingly.
All right! Leave it to me.
Huh? Where are you going, Naruto?
Isn't it obvious?
— To investigate the Cursed Warrior.
— What?
Oh, Chishima.
Naruto, just now...
It's nothing, it's nothing.
— Did you have business with us?
— Oh, yes.
You have all been so helpful
to me the whole time...
I feel so bad about that low payment.
Additional money?
We couldn't...
No, it's the specialty of
the Land of Birds.
Chicken-wing buns filled with bean jam.
Yakitori Tsurucho
Thanks.
Sure enough, this area's fishy.
It's kind of time-consuming
searching alone...
Summoning Jutsu.
Long time no see.
Are you giving me a snack?
Why is it you guys?
Dad's busy with stuff, so...
No, I can't have Boss Gama
appearing, either.
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
You guys have a better sense of smell
than humans, right?
You're calling us puppies?
Jeez. Toad authority
has sure hit rock bottom.
Gamatatsu, we're leaving.
Gamatatsu?
Hey, Gamatatsu!
A frog that pounces
on a willow leaf?
What are you doing, you idiot?
Big Brother Gamakichi!
I wonder what this is!
Whoa, it's dark! It's night!
Good night.
Good morning.
What's this?
It's a kite painted black.
— A kite?
— Look up there.
That's a totally huge kite.
I wonder if there was
a big kite-flying festival or something.
It's rather plain for a festival kite.
What? What does that mean?
— Oh, no!
— Hey. Where are you going?
I'm back.
I get it. If one were to fly that
in the cover of a dark night,
a Cursed Warrior hanging on
to the black kite
would look like he was flying.
With this, the mystery
of the flying warrior is solved,
Next...
Someone was here on that night.
What is it?
The Cursed Warrior came out from here.
It just looks like an old temple
that isn't used much at all.
— You're right.
— Let's go, Gamatatsu.
But, Big Brother Gamakichi,
it's nice and cool here.
What are you talking about?
In such a hot and humid temple...
Indeed, that's a nice damp wind.
See? Isn't it comfortable?
Draft from down below here?
What's this?
Wow, I wonder if a giant worm made this.
Or a mole.
All right, let's check it out.
I wonder how we should greet a mole
if we meet one.
Like I care.
So, Naruto is still investigating
the Cursed Warrior, huh?
I should probably inform Lord Moso.
There was some trouble caused,
but we have at last found a safe refuge.
After him!
Big brother, where are we?
This place is...
This is the residence
of the feudal lord, isn't it?
Really? Residence of the feudal lord?
No wonder it's an impressive building.
It was connected to this place?
What was that sound?
What a nice view.
Hey. What are you doing?
Keep quiet. We'll be discovered.
Big Brother Gamakichi!
You blockhead!
Good work with your duties.
As for me, I'm not anyone suspicious.
I was asked here
by Superintendent Moso and...
I'm investigating the incident...
It'll make sense
if I tell you about it.
Lord Sagi.
We have captured a suspicious man.
What shall we do with him?
What?
Sagi, bro. Hey.
We met at the lake, didn't we?
Explain to them about me.
I know no such person.
What?!
He's not worth sending
to the magistrate's office.
— Lock him in the dungeon.
— Yes, my lord.
Hey, that's harsh. Come on, Sagi!
Hey! Wait a minute! Come on! Hey!
Come on. This is a misunderstanding.
I was just going after the Cursed Warrior.
Everything will make sense
if you just ask Mr. Moso.
You okay?
Yo.
I can't be fighting the soldiers
of my employer's land.
Jeez. You had to go and get caught
in that trap.
Well, it's cool.
I can get out of a place like this
right away
if I just use both my hands.
— Hey, untie this.
— Right. Just a second.
Wha...?
The Cursed Warrior?
Damn it.
If I could just use both hands,
this guy would be...
Big Brother,
are we going to let things be?
If things go wrong,
we could be sliced in two.
I wouldn't want that.
Just a little more...
Just a little more.
Sagi?
What's going on here?
You're the other Cursed Warrior?
But why?
They say people become disembodied spirits
and avenge themselves
But that's a lie!
This watch has been handed down
from generation to generation
in the feudal-lord family.
It was supposed to be passed
from father to son.
But now, along with that death,
the watch has stopped ticking away.
It must have been very sad.
I am shamelessly living on
only for the sake of revenge.
I can go to hell
if I can just complete my revenge.
That's no good.
There is no way you could understand
how someone who's had everything
taken from them feels.
Like I know about stuff like that.
But I at least know that living
for the sake of revenge is wrong.
You're a feudal lord, aren't you?
Is revenge the job of a feudal lord?
You know that's not it.
The true culprit, Komei,
has been arrested.
You should just leave the rest to Moso.
Okay?
It is no concern of yours.
I must not let you live...
now that you have learned everything.
As a thief who snuck into the residence
of the feudal lord,
your fate is a death sentence.
No way.
This is creepy.
This is the tomb of the successive
generations of feudal lords, right?
Yeah. That's the tomb of the Lord Owashi.
Byakugan.
What's this?
What is it, Neji? What are you seeing?
There's something poisonous
in Owashi's body.
Was he assassinated?
We're surrounded.
An announcement to the ninja
from the Leaf Village.
A message has just been delivered
from the residence of the feudal lord.
Your comrade has been arrested
for infiltrating the residence
of the feudal lord,
and his death sentence
has been determined.
Leave the Land of Birds at once.
If you don't, you will be executed here
for the same crime.
It doesn't matter. Draw your bows.
— Neji, what should we do?
— Go to the residence of the feudal lord.
We're going to save Naruto.
You're...
Kakashi-sensei. Naruto's in trouble.
We have to go to the residence
of the feudal lord and save him.
We can't do that.
— Your mission is over.
— But...
Don't do anything
other than the mission.
dokomademo tsudzuku michi ni wa ironna koto arunda ne
so many things happen on this endless road, right?
tsuyogari na kimi ga kyou wa juwaki koshi ni namida koe
although you're strong-willed your voice wavered on the phone today
donna yume oikakete kokomade kitan darou
what dreams did you chase to get here?
wakara na kunattari suru koto wa boku ni datte aru kara nee BABY
even I have times when I just don't understand baby
kimi ga namida no toki ni wa boku ga soba ni iru kara
when you're sad I'll be close to you
hanareba nare no yoru datte boku wa soba ni iru kara
even on nights when we're apart I'll be close to you
boku wa soba ni iru kara
I'll be close to you
Are we really going back
to the village like this?
I told you. Our mission in
the Land of Birds is finished now.
But then, what'll happen
to Naruto?
We can't interfere with
this land's internal affairs.
No way...
Sorry. The responsibility rests
on me, the leader.
Let it go... Sacrifice is
a part of Shinobi missions.
Next time:
"Naruto Dies."